# **RÉSUMÉ**

## John Krug

Granada, Spain

Email: jh.krug@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jhkrug

GitHub: https://www.github.com/jhkrug GitLab: https://www.gitlab.com/libtics

Other: https://jhkrug.github.io

I'm an experienced information technology and documentation professional. I've worked in development, systems and data management, support, and technical documentation, often in mentoring and leadership roles.

Following a career pivot, six years ago, I have been enjoying technical writing and docs-as-code. First, at OutSystems, documenting a low-code product. Now at SUSE, documenting CNCF and cloud projects and products.

## **SKILLS**

I have been an employee, mentor, manager, and a director/owner so have a wide and empathic perspective.

I have worked in large and small teams in a range of organizations. For the past six years this has been fully remote documentation work with geographically dispersed, agile development teams. I use Git, GitHub, Markdown, Asciidoc, Docusaurus and Antora, and a variety of enterprise applications.

Prior to this, at Lancaster, I worked in system management, data management, Oracle, SQL, ETL processes, and data analytics and visualization. I applied these skills to library management and analytics processes. I held frequent training sessions for library staff and am comfortable helping people make best use of their tools.

I am very familiar with Linux, and have used Windows and MacOS. I have coded in many languages over the years (Assembly, C, OCCAM, SQL, Lua, Python, Shell, etc.). I have written much training material and documentation so the documentation pivot is a natural fit. I have, many, many times, learned new technologies, using and integrating them.

My first language is English. I'm learning Spanish and finding it difficult. Perseverance is key.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Technical Writer, SUSE, July 2023 - Present

Fully remote. I'm part of the SUSE Rancher cloud engineering division. I write documentation for open-source cloud products, working daily with engineers and project managers. My primary project is Kubewarden (CNCF sandbox). Documentation tools are GitHub, git, vsCode, Docusaurus and Markdown, and AsciiDoc and Antora. I work with our documentation tools group to make sure we make best use of these technologies.

I provide mentoring and guidance to new and less experienced team members.

I have presented at SUSECON24 and SUSECON25, in Berlin and Orlando, helping customers understand SUSE's approaches to documentation and make best use of it.

## Technical Writer, OutSystems, July 2022 - May 2023

Fully remote. I worked on product documentation for the OutSystems low-code product set. The products provided low-code workflow development tools. We used markdown, git, vsCode, and GitHub. I enjoyed being back in full-time work in a highly technical, client-focused organization.

## Library Consultant, Independent, May 2017 - July 2022

Fully remote. For the University of Leeds, I developed Alma and Primo data analytics training materials for library staff. The CC-licensed training materials website is at Libtics. The training materials are in Asciidoc and Antora with accompanying video material. The source is at GitLab.

In April 2018, I organized and presented at a training workshop on Alma Data Analytics for UK Ex Libris users in London on behalf of the British user group.

## Systems and Analytics Manager, Lancaster University Library, April 2002 - March 2017

I had 15 years at Lancaster University Library, starting as the Library Systems Manager implementing a newly purchased Ex Libris library management system based on Oracle.

For IGeLU[1] and ELUNA[2], I established the Data Analytics group[3] to promote use of Alma Data Analytics in HE libraries. I coordinated 14 library professionals around the world helping build the wider Ex Libris Data Analytics community at conferences and workshops.

I gained an ILM Level 5 qualification in leadership and management. I received a Lancaster University staff award for outstanding achievement.

#### Before 2002

- With colleagues, I started a consultancy, Xinetica Ltd (1996-2002). We did well, for a few years, before the first internet crash and internal rifts. I worked at ASDA and the Financial Services Authority.
- I was a consultant at Protek (1994-1996) working at North West Water.
- I was a systems administrator at Barclays de Zoet Wedd (1992-1993) in London. I worked on the FX derivatives desk. A high pressure environment.
- During 1991, after my M.Sc. I worked at the NTSC[4] with parallel processing industrial research and the INMOS transputer.
- I was a Lance Corporal in the British Army (1983-86). I can drive a tracked armored personnel carrier if necessary:-).

## **EDUCATION**

- 1990-1991 University of Sheffield, M.Sc. Software Systems Technology
- 1985-1989 Open University (UK), undergraduate courses at in mathematics and computing.

## **REFERENCES**

## **PORTFOLIO**

- GitHub: https://www.github.com/jhkrug
- GitLab: https://gitlab.com/libtics
- Libtics: https://libtics.netlify.app
- A very occasional blog: https://jhkrug.github.io.

## **FOOTNOTES**

- 1 International Group of Ex Libris Users
- 2 Ex Libris Users of North America
- 3 Analytics SIWG (Special Interest Working Group)
- 4 National Transputer Support Centre in Sheffield. Funded to promote parallel processing using the INMOS Transputer. The Transputer was a microprocessor with facilities enabling easy parallelism when connected with other transputers.